<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Working Papers | Candace Jens</title>
    <link>https://candacejens.github.io/working/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://candacejens.github.io/working/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Working Papers</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://candacejens.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Working Papers</title>
      <link>https://candacejens.github.io/working/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credit Market Driven Acquisitions</title>
      <link>https://candacejens.github.io/working/gulenjensrossi-mergers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://candacejens.github.io/working/gulenjensrossi-mergers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Winner of &amp;ldquo;Best Paper in Finance&amp;rdquo; Award, FMARC Conference, 2024&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a comprehensive sample of takeovers from 1983-2020, we show that credit market conditions predict takeover activity.  A deterioration in aggregate credit quality predicts an increase in the number and aggregate value of takeovers in years two and three, particularly for cash-financed deals, and lower activity in years five and six.  We find similar results in international samples and when omitting the financial crisis.  Worse aggregate credit quality predicts higher firm-level debt issuance and probability of a cash-financed deal announcement over the following three quarters. Our results are consistent with a framework with biased credit market investors and rational managers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=4075202&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SSRN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Controlling for group-level heterogeneity in causal forest</title>
      <link>https://candacejens.github.io/working/jenspagereeder-forestfixed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 01:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://candacejens.github.io/working/jenspagereeder-forestfixed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Causal forest is part of a growing class of doubly-robust machine learning based estimators that non-parametrically recovers heterogeneity in treatment effects. However, causal forest&amp;rsquo;s usefulness is currently limited because the group-level heterogeneity present in many economics settings violates a key assumption of causal forest required for the recovery of unbiased effects. We provide a solution: estimate group-level fixed effects in a regression, create a vector of fixed effects coefficients, and include this vector in the casual forest estimation. Monte Carlo simulations show our solution’s success and the shortcomings of alternatives. Our study greatly increases the number of settings in which unbiased, heterogeneous treatment effects are recoverable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3907601&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SSRN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change in capitol: How a 60 Minutes exposé and the STOCK Act affected the investment activity of U.S. Senators</title>
      <link>https://candacejens.github.io/working/cherryheitzjens-stock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://candacejens.github.io/working/cherryheitzjens-stock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2905309&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SSRN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
